So say, you want a chance to reap the potential financial rewards of investment in stock.
假设你想通过投资股票获利
Where do you start? Well, usually,
该如何开始呢？通常
you find a brokerage.
你需要找个证券经销商
A brokerage company functions as a middleman connecting buyers and sellers.
券商充当买方和卖方的中间人
However, they usually charge fees to complete transactions.
但是 通常券商需要收取交易费用
It is also sometimes possible to buy stock directly from companies.
有时候还可以直接从公司那购买股票
In this case, you don't have to use or pay commissions to a broker,
在这种情形下 你不需要聘请经纪人或向对方支付佣金
but you have less control over the price and timing of your purchase.
但是你对股价和交易时间的控制力更低
You can't buy or sell at a specific market price or at a specific time.
你无法以特定的市场价格或在特定时间买入或卖出
Typically, the company buys or sells shares for
通常 企业在指定的时间
the plan at set times and at an average market price,
以平均市场价格买入或卖出计划的股票
but how the shares are purchased depends on the company and the details of the plan.
但是股票的购买方式取决于企业和计划详情
Once you've bought some stock,
买了股票后
you'll be very interested in the patterns of changes in
你将对股价走势非常感兴趣
its price because in order to make money from your investment,
因为要通过投资获利
you want to sell it when its price is higher than when you bought it.
你需要以比买入价更高的价格卖出股票
A great deal of effort has gone into predicting when the price of a stock will go up.
你将花费大量精力预测股价何时会上涨
In order to follow your stock,
为了跟踪你的股票
you'll look up its unique symbol or ticker.
你需要查询股票代码
Alphabets unique symbol is GOOG,
Alphabet 的股票代码是 GOOG
Apples ticker is AAPL.
Apple 的股票代码是 AAPL
This is a price graph of Alphabet stock from 2005 until September 2017.
这是从 2005 年到 2017 年 9 月的 Alphabet 股价走势图
While the graph seems to progress upwards,
虽然股价总体是上升的
it isn't a steady or linear climb.
但是并不稳定或呈线性上升
The history of a stock's price is important and
历史股价很重要
potentially an indicator of how the stock will do in the future.
过去的股价可能对未来的走势有指示作用
As such, price histories have been studied by
所以投资者和交易员会研究
investors and traders since stocks were first traded.
从股票第一次交易起的股价历史记录
But when was that?
股票是从什么时候开始出现的？
How did all this get started in the first place?
一开始怎么就出现了股票？
Some people trace the history of stock back to
有些人将股票历史一直追溯到罗马共和国时代
the Roman Republic when the state contracted out many of
当时的罗马政府将很多服务
its services to private companies which issued
承包给了私有企业
shares to individuals to help with government services.
这些企业向帮助提供政府服务的个人发行了股票
In the early 1600s,
在 17 世纪初
the Dutch East India Company became the first company in
荷兰东印度公司成为第一家
history to issue bonds and shares of stock to the general public.
向公众发行债券和股票的公司
The company established the Amsterdam Stock Exchange in
该公司在 1602 年成立了阿姆斯特丹证券交易所
1602 as a forum for trade of securities.
这是一个交易证券的平台
The Amsterdam Stock Exchange pictured here could
图中的阿姆斯特丹证券交易所
be called the first incarnation of a modern stock market.
被喻为第一个现代股票交易所
Patterns in market activity have been studied since markets
从市场最早时期开始 人们就在研究市场活动的规律
earliest days and some patterns have been observed to repeat.
并且发现有些规律会重复
One of the most interesting market phenomena is the market bubble.
最有趣的一个市场现象是市场泡沫
Bubbles occur when market participants drive stock prices
当市场参与者将股价推高
above their value in relation to some system evaluation.
并高于某种系统评估值时 就会出现泡沫
There are notable similarities between
几个世纪前出现了一次郁金香球茎泡沫
the tulip bulb bubble which took place for centuries ago and saw the value of
一颗郁金香球茎的价格几乎达到技术工人的年度工资的 10 倍
a single tulip bulb grow to nearly 10 times the annual wage of
在 2000 年代初还出现了一次互联网公司泡沫
a skilled worker and the.com bubble which occurred in the early 2000s.
这两次泡沫之间有明显的相似性
The similarities in the graphs are fascinating and academics from
这两幅图之间的相似性很吸引人
behavioral economists to theoretical mathematicians have
行为经济学家和理论数学家等学者
devised captivating theories as to why bubbles might happen.
针对为何会出现泡沫提出了精彩的理论
One of the earliest works Extraordinary Popular Delusions and the Madness of
苏格兰记者 Charles Mackay 早在 1841 年
Crowds was published by Scottish journalists Charles Mackay way back in 1841.
就发表了一篇文章 叫做《Extraordinary Popular Delusions and the Madness of Crowds》
If you're interested in reading more about market bubbles or understanding
如果你想深入了解市场泡沫
the forces driving markets which are not explained by standard quantitative models,
或了解推动市场的因素 而标准量化模型没有做出解释
I'd suggest the work of Robert Shiller and Nassim Taleb.
建议阅读 Robert Shiller 和 Nassim Taleb 的作品